{
  "ch_wel_ggd_1": {
    "question": "On average, how much do children aged 8 to 16 in Luxembourg agree with the statement “All is well in my life”, on a scale from 0 to 10?",
    "choices": [
      "8.1",
      "6.5",
      "9.8",
      "4.5"
    ],
    "answer": "8.1"
  },
  "ch_wel_ggd_2": {
    "question": "On average, girls are more satisfied with their lives than boys?",
    "choices": [
      "Boys and girls report similar level of well-being.",
      "Yes, girls report higher level of well-being.",
      "No, girls report lower level of well-being."
    ],
    "answer": "No, girls report lower level of well-being."
  },
  "ch_wel_ppc_1": {
    "question": "Parents are often the people who know their children best. In Luxembourg, do you think parents on average overstate, understate or are able to correctly estimate their children’s wellbeing?",
    "choices": [
      "Parents understate their children's wellbeing (as compared to what children self-report)",
      "Parents overstate their children's wellbeing (as compared to what children self-report)",
      "Parents and children report similar levels of child wellbeing",
      "I’m not sure, but I’d like to find out"
    ],
    "answer": "Parents understate their children's wellbeing (as compared to what children self-report)"
  },
  "ad_fam_efp_1": {
    "question": "A major parental leave policy reform took place in Luxembourg in 2016. LISER evaluated the effect of the reform on parental leave take-up behaviour. Whose parental leave take-up increased the most after the reform?",
    "choices": [
      "Mothers",
      "Fathers",
      "None",
      "Both equally"
    ],
    "answer": "Fathers"
  },
  "ad_fam_efp_2": {
    "question": "LISER studies have analysed the factors that affect parental leave take-up among parents, including how employers’ characteristics influence uptake. In which type of firms is the take-up lowest?",
    "choices": [
      "The take-up does not differ depending on employer size",
      "Employers with fewer than 50 employees",
      "Employers with 50 to 100 employees",
      "Employers with more than 100 employees"
    ],
    "answer": "Employers with fewer than 50 employees"
  },
  "ch_pov_cpp_1": {
    "question": "According to our data, a child can feel poor…",
    "choices": [
      "Only if their family income is below the poverty line",
      "Even if their family income is not below the poverty line",
      "Only if they are materially deprived (ex. lack of clothes in good conditions, things needed for sport and leisure activities, books…)"
    ],
    "answer": "Even if their family income is not below the poverty line"
  },
  "ch_pov_cpp_2": {
    "question": "Which factor is a strong predictor of children feeling poor, even when they are not?",
    "choices": [
      "Age",
      "Number of siblings",
      "Gender"
    ],
    "answer": "Gender"
  },
  "ch_pov_ecg_1": {
    "question": "In 2024, Luxembourg ranks in terms of child poverty and social exclusion among:",
    "choices": [
      "The 8 EU best performers",
      "The 8 EU worst performers"
    ],
    "answer": "The 8 EU worst performers"
  },
  "ch_pov_ecg_2": {
    "question": "In 2024, In Luxembourg the vast majority of children “at risk of poverty or social exclusion” live:",
    "choices": [
      "In a low-income household",
      "With jobless parents",
      "In a severely deprived household"
    ],
    "answer": "In a low-income household"
  },
  "ad_ine_gicc_1": {
    "question": "Which of these hypothetical green policies is supported by more women than men?",
    "choices": [
      "Increasing the VAT on red meat from 3% to 17%",
      "Introducing a 5-euro highway toll",
      "Rationing on fossil energy sources",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "Rationing on fossil energy sources"
  },
  "ad_ine_gicc_2": {
    "question": "Why are women more vulnerable to the impacts of inflation in Luxembourg?",
    "choices": [
      "Women typically have less access to financial resources like savings to manage unexpected expenses",
      "Women tend to allocate a larger share of their income to essential goods and services, such as food and heating",
      "Single parents, who typically face lower average incomes and reduced capacity to absorb rising costs, are predominantly women",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  "ch_edu_esse_1": {
    "question": "Which region in Luxembourg has the least number of secondary schools?",
    "choices": [
      "Région Centre",
      "Région Sud",
      "Région Nord",
      "Région Est"
    ],
    "answer": "Région Est"
  },
  "ch_edu_esse_2": {
    "question": "In which year did the law on primary education begin to include parents’ preferences for track placement (ESC, ESG, ESG-VO) when moving from primary to secondary school?",
    "choices": [
      "2003",
      "2009",
      "2015",
      "2023"
    ],
    "answer": "2009"
  },
  "sn_hea_shar_1": {
    "question": "The percentage of the total population that are over 50 years old in Luxembourg is",
    "choices": [
      "25%",
      "35%",
      "45%"
    ],
    "answer": "35%"
  },
  "sn_hea_shar_2": {
    "question": "The percentage of the total population that are over 65 years old in Luxembourg is",
    "choices": [
      "Less than 10%",
      "More than 14%",
      "More than 20%"
    ],
    "answer": "More than 14%"
  },
  "sn_hea_papf_1": {
    "question": "In Luxembourg, more than 1.25% of the total population is affected by dementia. This share is projected to...",
    "choices": [
      "Be the same in 2050",
      "Reach 2.04% of the population",
      "Reach 2.44% of the total population"
    ],
    "answer": "Reach 2.44% of the total population"
  },
  "sn_hea_papf_2": {
    "question": "Luxembourg has similar dementia prevalence rates than",
    "choices": [
      "Belgium",
      "Cyprus",
      "France"
    ],
    "answer": "Cyprus"
  },
  "sn_wel_ppp_1": {
    "question": "On average, what additional share of their pension savings did participants in our study say they would give up for a portable pension plan?",
    "choices": [
      "1.2%",
      "3.6%",
      "5.2%",
      "2.4%"
    ],
    "answer": "3.6%"
  },
  "sn_wel_ppp_2": {
    "question": "In our study, which group was more willing to pay extra for a portable pension plan?",
    "choices": [
      "People over 40",
      "Cross-border workers living in Belgium",
      "People who are not homeowners",
      "Women"
    ],
    "answer": "People over 40"
  },
  "sn_wel_saa_1": {
    "question": "Looking beyond the average score, the <strong>Active Ageing Index (AAI)</strong> also tells us how evenly older adults benefit from active ageing opportunities. Greater inequality in AAI scores means weaker overall performance.<br><br>Where do you think <strong>Luxembourg</strong> ranks among 28 European countries for <strong>AAI equality</strong>?",
    "choices": [
      "3rd",
      "10th",
      "6th",
      "15th"
    ],
    "answer": "6th"
  },
  "sn_wel_saa_2": {
    "question": "In <strong>LISER</strong>, we have estimated the <strong>Active Ageing Index</strong> for persons aged 55+ in 28 EU countries with data from 2016-2017.<br><br><strong>Guess the Rank!</strong><br>Based on its average <strong>Active Ageing Index (AAI)</strong> score, where do you think Luxembourg stands among 28 European countries?",
    "choices": [
      "12th",
      "5th",
      "18th",
      "2nd"
    ],
    "answer": "5th"
  }
}